Emilio Quiambao

Software Developer

San Francisco, CA

emilioq.github.io

emilioquiambao@gmail.com (650) 296-3335

Projects

Environmental Hazard Website

Developed an environmental hazard website from scratch with a team of seven students. Worked as full stack developer and back-end lead. Created vertical prototype with Django framework and MySQL Workbench on AWS Server. Documented project milestones.

Webcam Music

An app created in a 24-hour hackathon using Processing. Webcam is used to create music based on pictures taken.

Particle Life

Inspired by Conway's Game of Life, a javascript app utilizing particles to simulate organic movement.

Android Event Browser

Android app developed using Android Studio. Implements Meetup and Volley API. Able to search and display info retrieved from Meetup API in a card list.

ASCII Maze Solver

Receives an ASCII maze file and displays it correspondingly in graphics. A solution is then generated and a character sprite follows the path.

Data Wrangler Management Project

A real world I.T. project management case of a data wrangling software. Created the business case, project infrastructure, scope management plan, work breakdown structure, schedule, and budget.

Work Experience

The X Kids

Technology Camp School Instructor Feb 2017 - Aug 2017 | San Francisco, CA

- » Taught kids robotics, coding, and chess.
- » Ages range from kindergarten to middle school.

San Francisco SPCA

Shelter, Special Events, and Matchmaking Volunteer
July 2016 – Aug 2017 | San Francisco, CA

- » Contributed 50+ hrs at an animal shelter.
- » Helped clients looking to adopt.
- » Maintained animal database.

Skills

Software Engineering Process

Knowledge of full SE lifecycle including common and best practices for SE teamwork and SE processes

Programming Languages

Java JavaScript Python HTML & CSS C, C++ SQL Lua

Software Tools

Django Bootstrap Git, GitHub VirtualBox MySQL Workbench Android Studio

Project Management

Slack Trello Agile/Scrum Skype, Zoom SAP, MS Project User-centered design

Education

San Francisco State University

BS in Computer Science | Aug 2014 - Dec 2018 GPA: 3.59

University of Seoul

BS in Computer Science | Aug 2017 - Jan 2018

Activities

Association for Computer Machinery

Organization where engineer and CS students share projects, ideas, and tech news.

International Education Exchange Council

Student organization encouraging international education, student exchange and sharing of cultures between international and domestic students.

SF State Exchange Program

Studied abroad in Seoul, Korea for a semester with GKS scholarship. Studied artifical intelligence.